Contact

smarifinul@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/s-m-arifinul-karim-246b0276 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Networking Telecommunications Network Design

Languages

English (Full Professional)
Hindi (Limited Working)
Bengali (Native or Bilingual)

Honors-Awards

Chairman's Award
IEEE Project
Special Achievement Award

S. M. Arifinul Karim

Optical Transmission Planner

Bangladesh

Summary

I am involved in the Telecommunication field of Bangladesh since 2010 and looking for a challenging position within a progressive organization, where I can utilize my leadership, knowledge, experience, technical skills, creativity and share with team members and colleagues, and try to increase the competence and prestige of the profession.

Experience

Summit Communications Ltd 10 years

Manager

July 2019 - Present (1 year 7 months)

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Deputy Manager

January 2015 - July 2019 (4 years 7 months)

Dhaka

- Formulation of Technology strategy aligning with SCL's strategy, vision, and objectives.
- Leading Planning and Design of IP/MPLS, DWDM &SDH Network to ensure network scalability and

high availability

- Responsible for Network Capacity Forecast and Budget
- Perform HLD, LLD, BOQ Preparation, TDM/Packet/WDM Service Planning, Traffic Migration

Planning, DCN Planning, Synchronization Planning, Software Up-gradation Planning, Network

Inspection (Health Check), etc.

 Leading Transmission Team to deliver the project. Also, prepare end to end implementation plan

according to the target schedule

- Diagnosis of different alarm observed on SDH/DWDM circuits.
- · DCN network planning and optimization.

- DCN and Sync plan provide and fault rectification of SDH network
- Leading IP/MPLS and DWDM Implementation team during the deployment phase.
- Coordination with vendors for system and network architecture and designrelated issues.
- Provide 2nd & 3rd level technical support for Installation, Testing and Commissioning, Integration,

Up-gradation, Acceptance Test, Troubleshooting, Operation & Maintenance, Project Management

and regular activities of transport network equipment.

- · Lead nationwide optical fiber network project.
- Evaluate new technology, service, and equipment.
- Communication & Coordination with customer for technical clarification and deliberations,

identifying potential and conflicting issues and seeking fair and transparent resolutions

- Technical Coordination with Service & Solution Team during the submission of technical proposal and bidding session.
- Responsible for preparing MoP, RFQ /RFP and Solution.
- Supervise team members and provide necessary training.

Assistant Manager

January 2013 - December 2014 (2 years)

Dhaka

- Installation, testing, commissioning, integration, operation & maintenance of IP and SDH Network product.
- Conducting PAT of IP and SDH products.
- Conducting IP and SDH fault analysis.
- Equipment health checking before any major operation.
- Responsible for optical fiber network project
- Commissioning and service activation for Telco and ISP clients.
- Service KPI parameter testing and required troubleshooting.
- L2VPN and L3VPN service activation in SCL IP/MPLS core network
- Fiber network survey and feasibility analysis.

Assistant Engineer

February 2011 - December 2012 (1 year 11 months)

- Commissioning and service activation for Telco and ISP client.
- Service KPI parameter testing and required troubleshooting.

- L2VPN and L3VPN service activation in SCL IP/MPLS core network
- Fiber network survey and feasibility analysis

Flora Limited Assistant Systems Engineer July 2010 - January 2011 (7 months)

Dhaka

- •Design, implementation & troubleshooting of corporate LAN and WAN.
- •Provide hardware and software installation, configuration and maintenance support for HP and Dell Servers.
- •Installation & troubleshooting of Windows Server (2003, 2008) and service pack.
- •Installation & troubleshooting of Linux.
- Commissioning and integration of Active Directory.
- •Planning, designing and implementing mission-critical projects based on customer requirements.
- •Provide consulting for enterprise projects in a heterogeneous environment.
- •Ensures best practice for Server Virtualization an, Windows and Linux platform

Education

East West University

Master of Business Administration -EMBA, Operations Management · (2017 - 2019)

American International University-Bangladesh Bachelor of Science (BSc), Electrical and Electronics Engineering · (2006 - 2010)

BCIC College

Science · (1994 - 2003)